<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jimmy Young</title>
    <description>// Portfolio</description>
    <link>jyng.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="jyng.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 22:26:02 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 22:26:02 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making it easier to reduce food's carbon impact</title>
        <description>
&lt;div class=&quot;center measure-wide ph3 ph3-sm ph0-l f5 lh-copy text&quot;&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;MyDomino’s mission is to help people reduce their carbon impact. But getting people to reduce their carbon impact is hard because there are so many moving parts: Going solar, reducing food waste, switching to renewable energy — the options are varied.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We decided to build out a guided path that makes the whole process of reducing carbon emissions easy and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;the-product&quot;&gt;The Product&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Our product is divided into 3 different categories: Food, Transportation, Energy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We started with food first because it was something that a lot of users were curious about. We figured we could use that curiosity to our advantage and build repertoire before moving onto larger/other categories.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In terms with how it works, it’s food tracking but measured in carbon footprint. We realized early on that many people are curious about reducing their carbon footprint, but they don’t know much about it. Our product prioritized the learning of the relationship of food and carbon footprint, while using competition to create a compelling experience.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I was responsible for designing the product from sketching to shipping. I also supported in user research duties and front-end development.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;wireframes&quot;&gt;Wireframes&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I started by organizing Actions and Information into specific hierarchies and then iterated in a Crazy 8s fashion to quickly generate ideas.
I then took the best ideas so see how well they held up on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-column flex-wrap flex-row-ns justify-around center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100 w-33-ns&quot; src=&quot;assets/food-challenge/wireframes-1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;w-100 w-33-ns&quot; src=&quot;assets/food-challenge/wireframes-2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;w-100 w-33-ns&quot; src=&quot;assets/food-challenge/wireframes-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;db center tc mono gray f6 mt0  mb5&quot;&gt; Input UI explorations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center measure-wide ph3 ph3-sm ph0-l f5 lh-copy text&quot;&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-design&quot;&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We decided on a data visualization design that placed focus on a user’s food impact progress. Below the progress tile, we also offered other resources such as helpful articles and local events in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw7 ph3 center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/food-challenge/myhome-v1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw7 ph3 center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;assets/food-challenge/hover.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;center tc mono gray f6 mt0 mb5&quot;&gt; Hover interaction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw7 ph3 center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;/assets/food-challenge/foodModal@1.5x.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;center tc mono gray f6 mt0 mb5&quot;&gt;The dynamic gauge gives instant feedback on their carbon impact (Prototyped in Framer)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center measure-wide ph3 ph3-sm ph0-l f5 lh-copy text&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In the food view, after a user finishes food input flow, they are brought back to the dashboard. We felt that this experience created a dead-end without enough incentive for the user to return.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I suggested that we should do some user interviews even if the product wasn’t fully functional to test our assumption. I supported user research by distilling findings into insights.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here are some insights we found:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Measurement for carbon dioxide wasn’t a clear indicator of how well they were doing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There wasn’t enough context for the graph to be meaningful&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The gauge was easy to miss because it was below the fold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;My product manager suggested a week graph as that UI is clearer than  . Our engineers were working on some back-end issues, so I designed and implemented the feature.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We also noticed that the graph would be a lot of valuable once users have established context. I suggested we move the graph into the results view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw7 ph3 center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;https://canvas-files-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/765259d3-f505-4557-9b53-d95472ea333a/My-Home%20%207a%20.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;https://canvas-files-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/3f945c0b-b83c-4676-ae3e-5b189c6dfc5d/desktop 1f--flip.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center measure-wide ph3 ph3-sm ph0-l f5 lh-copy text&quot;&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;style-guide--front-end-architecture&quot;&gt;Style Guide &amp;amp; Front-End Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While building the product, I documented our design patterns into a style guide and led the CSS architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw7 ph3 center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;https://canvas-files-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/9353e7ef-5a35-407e-8891-e119ab43d110/Desktop.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;https://canvas-files-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/740e0aa2-845c-4f36-bd1d-f7c04344bc77/Page 2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mw7 ph3 center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-100&quot; src=&quot;https://canvas-files-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/aa9fbee6-8bf6-4824-ac89-7a27e137d3dd/Screen Shot 2017-04-03 at 7.55.12 PM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>jyng.github.io/food-challenge</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">jyng.github.io/food-challenge</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 22:43:32 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>jyng.github.io/welcome-to-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">jyng.github.io/welcome-to-jekyll</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a more efficient method for processing sexual offenses</title>
        <description>
&lt;div class=&quot;center measure-wide ph3 ph3-sm ph0-l f5 lh-copy text&quot;&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;problem&quot;&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The process of putting together a sexual assault case currently fails the purposes of advocating for victims and bringing perpetrators to hand. This problem can be improved by building a better intake and management system. Here’s an overview of the current situation:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;To initiate the case, the SANE (Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner) Nurse examines the victim. The results of the examination are sealed inside of a Sexual Assault Kit (SAK).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The SAK goes through a process of medical examination. The findings are meant to support the identification of perpetrator(s) and to provide evidence for a potential trial.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;After the SAK gets processed, an investigator is assigned to pursue the case.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The investigator finds the perpetrator, brings them to trial, and concludes the case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Sounds great, right? However, the reality is that investigators rarely get the necessary information to proceed with the case. There is always a large backlog of SAK that might never see an investigator.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In one weekend, my team and I sought to address this bottleneck by building a Minimum Viable Product (MVP) for product validation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;sketching&quot;&gt;Sketching&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I communicated the design through sketching first. This enables us to quickly draw out potential solutions while keeping design overhead low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-column flex-row-ns mw7 center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;sketch dashboard&quot; src=&quot;/assets/vivifi/sketch_dashboard.jpg&quot; class=&quot;w-90  ba b--silver&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;sketch information&quot; src=&quot;/assets/vivifi/sketch_information.jpg&quot; class=&quot;w-90 ba b--silver&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center measure-wide ph3 ph3-sm ph0-l f5 lh-copy text&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We were also able to quickly throw out inferior solutions as well. This pop-up solution increased the complexity of the product and expensive for engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col col-12 mb4&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;sketch popup&quot; src=&quot;../assets/sketch_popup.jpg&quot; class=&quot;fit rounded&quot; style=&quot;max-height:25em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We determined that the biggest problem was how information was being distributed between professionals. Our proposed management system is aimed toward bridging the gaps between people and making the process as efficient as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/vivifi_dashboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;vivifi dashboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-record&quot;&gt;Creating a record&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;SANE Nurses initiate cases, but they have legal limitations on their access of information:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;They cannot edit the cases after it has been submitted&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;They cannot view other cases&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To account for these limitations, we decided to separate “SANE Nurse” and “Investigator” types where SANE Nurses can only create new records and Investigators can create and view records.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/vivifi_create.png&quot; alt=&quot;vivifi create&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Because SANE Nurses can only create new records, we have a “Review” button to help them confirm that they’ve entered the information accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/vivifi_review.png&quot; alt=&quot;vivifi review&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;investigating-a-case&quot;&gt;Investigating a case&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After a case has been submitted, the case shows up on the dashboard (which only the investigator may see). The investigator can then proceed to look through each case and fill out the information they’ve collected. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/vivifi_victim.png&quot; alt=&quot;vivifi victim&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Once an investigator presses “Complete,” an automated email message is sent to the victim to update them on the progress of their case.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We built this project during a snowy weekend near Lake Tahoe, so it’s definitely a small application. Still, we solved our scope of the problem (increasing transparency of information) and even squeezed in a nifty feature (email updates).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;With an MVP built out, we’re beginning to do some product validation with small counties in the Midwest. We’re also planning on starting a Kickstarter campaign so there will be second version coming out soon.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-learned&quot;&gt;3 Lessons Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;designing-in-the-browser-reduces-engineering-cost&quot;&gt;1. Designing in the Browser Reduces Engineering Cost&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I used a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tachyons.io/&quot;&gt;Tachyons spacing module&lt;/a&gt; on top of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bootswatch.com/paper/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap theme&lt;/a&gt; in which Tachyons’ atomic classes really showed big gains without conflicting the Bootstrap CSS (It’s amazing what margin and padding can do alone). At first, I was unused to using a application outside of Sketch, but I soon found out that I was building things faster than I would have in Sketch. It’s amazing what margin and padding can do alone. From this, I learned how utility classes can enable designers to contribute on production code. Relieving engineers from coding pixel-perfect designs is a huge win in
my book.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;ux-freebies-from-mean-stack-ultimately-helps-our-users&quot;&gt;2. UX Freebies from MEAN Stack Ultimately Helps Our Users&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We ultimately chose MEAN stack, but we had disagreements about choosing MEAN over Rails. Although I was more familiar with Ruby on Rails, I now understand why we chose MEAN. Take a look at this interaction:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/vivifi_interaction.gif&quot; alt=&quot;vivifi interaction&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This search input allows us to remove having an “Enter” button, which mean users can get to what they want faster and it comes for free!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Because MEAN processes most of its information on the client side, we can minimize clicks to help users achieve their goals easier. With our heavy focus on input fields, choosing MEAN enabled us to make a simpler application with less friction for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;user-stories-guide-our-scope&quot;&gt;3. User Stories Guide Our Scope&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A significant obstacle in hack projects is deciding what can be reasonably built in 1-2 days. By engaging user stories in the ideation and planning phases, we were able to organize and complete features efficiently while keeping a holistic view of the project’s scope.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;For example, a user story we really wanted was for victims to engage with the investigator on the progress of their case. This user story came up multiple times in conversation, but other user stories proved to have higher priority. Building out a “victim dashboard” would require the same amount of time. Also, the product wouldn’t be able to exist if investigators had no information to pursue cases.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/vivifi_trello.png&quot; alt=&quot;vivifi trello&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>jyng.github.io/vivifi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">jyng.github.io/vivifi</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
